Guide to the Botswana Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Botswana collection
1898-2009
MS 1504
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6.02
(6 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material relating to political and social conditions, and development in Botswana.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection (MS 605); Pamphlet Collection (MS 1351); African Postcard Collection (MS 1575). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The material in the first accession is arranged chronologically. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material relating to political and social conditions, and development in Botswana.
Education -- Botswana; Police -- Botswana; Rural development -- Botswana; Women -- Botswana; Botswana -- Description and travel; Botswana -- Economic conditions; Botswana -- Politics and government; Botswana -- Rural conditions; Botswana -- Social conditions
- Inventory, 1937-1992
  - Raditladi Commission of Enquiry: transcript and reports, 1937 December (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Handbook of Tswana Law and Custom, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 2-5)
  - Speeches by government officials, [1951?]-1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Government documents and reports, 1953-1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General information brochures; pamphlets; booklets, 1957-1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General information brochures; pamphlets; booklets, 1989-1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Social welfare organizations: newsletters; reports, 1980-1991 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Periodicals: including economic and political monthlies, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Journals: cultural and academic, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Additional Material, 1898, 1946-1996; Accession 1995-M-167
  - General information, brochures, pamphlets, 1973, [199?], undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bechuanaland Protectorate, 1946, 1964, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Botswana Police Force Newsletter," vol. 2, no. 2, vol. 3, no. 3, 1995, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bourne, H. R. Fox, The Bechuana Troubles: A Story of Pledge-Breaking, Rebel-Making and Slave-Making in a British Colony, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Brigades Bopang Botswana," Department of Vocational Education and Training newsletter, 1978 Oct, 1994 December (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chobe game reserve regulations, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Government reports and inquiries, 1974, 1977, 1987, 1990, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Khama, Seretse, Sir, speeches and writings, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - University of Botswana, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Williamson, D., Botswana—Environmental Policies and Practices under Scrutiny, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "The Women's Manifesto: A Summary of Botswana Women's Issues and Demands", 1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Additional material, 1969-2009; Accession 2015-M-001
  - Printed material, 1969-2009 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Posters, 2000s (Folder 3, Box 2, Folder 1)